[
{"question": "\r\n                                What is COVID-19?\r\n                            ", "response": "COVID-19 is the infectious disease caused by the coronavirus, SARS-CoV-2, which is a respiratory pathogen. WHO first learned of this new virus from cases in Wuhan, People\u2019s Republic of China on 31 December 2019."},
{"question": "\r\n                                What are the symptoms of COVID-19?\r\n                            ", "response": "The most common symptoms of COVID-19 are"},
{"question": "\r\n                                What happens to people who get seriously ill?\r\n                            ", "response": "Most people (about 80%) recover from the disease without needing hospital treatment. About 20% of those who get COVID-19 become seriously ill and require oxygen, with 5% becoming critically ill and needing intensive care."},
{"question": "\r\n                                Who is most at risk of severe illness from COVID-19?\r\n                            ", "response": "People aged 60 and over, and those with underlying medical problems like high blood pressure, heart and lung problems, diabetes, obesity or cancer, are at higher risk of developing serious illness.\u00a0"},
{"question": "\r\n                                How can we protect others and ourselves if we don't know who is infected?\r\n                            ", "response": "Stay safe by taking some simple precautions, such as physical distancing, wearing a mask, keeping rooms well ventilated, avoiding crowds, cleaning your hands, and coughing into a bent elbow or tissue. Check local advice where you live and work. "},
{"question": "\r\n                                When should I get a test for COVID-19?\r\n                            ", "response": "Anyone with symptoms should be tested, wherever possible. People who do not have symptoms but have had close contact with someone who is, or may be, infected may also consider testing \u2013 check with your local health guidelines. While a person is\n    waiting for test results, they should remain isolated from others. Where testing capacity is limited, tests should first be done for those at higher risk of infection, such as health workers, and those at higher risk of severe illness such as older\n    people, especially those living in seniors\u2019 residences or long-term care facilities."},
{"question": "\r\n                                What test should I get to see if I have COVID-19?\r\n                            ", "response": "In most situations, a molecular test is used to detect SARS-CoV-2 and confirm COVID-19.\u00a0Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) is the most commonly used molecular test. Samples are collected from the nose and/or throat with a swab. Molecular tests detect\n    virus in the sample by amplifying viral genetic material to detectable levels. For this reason, a molecular test is used to confirm an active infection, usually within a few days of exposure and around the time that symptoms may begin.\u00a0"},
{"question": "\r\n                                What about rapid tests?\r\n                            ", "response": "Rapid tests (sometimes known as a rapid diagnostic test \u2013 RDT) detect viral proteins (known as antigens). Samples are collected from the nose and/or throat with a swab. These tests are cheaper than PCR and will offer results more quickly, although\n    they are generally less accurate. We are still learning about how well they perform and when to use them."},
{"question": "\r\n                                I want to find out if I had COVID-19 in the past, what test should I take?\r\n                            ", "response": "Antibody tests can tell us whether someone has had an infection in the past, even if they have not had symptoms. Also known as serological tests and usually done on a blood sample, these tests detect antibodies produced in response to an infection. In\n    most people, antibodies start to develop after days to weeks and can indicate if a person has had recent (IgM type antibodies) or past infection (IgG type). Antibody tests cannot be used to diagnose COVID-19 in the early stages of infection or disease.\n    They also cannot alone confirm immunity or duration of protection from reinfection."},
{"question": "\r\n                                What is the difference between isolation and quarantine?\r\n                            ", "response": "Both isolation and quarantine are methods of preventing the spread of the disease."},
{"question": "\r\n                                What should I do if I have been exposed to someone who has COVID-19?\r\n                            ", "response": "If you have been exposed to someone with COVID-19, you may become infected, even if you feel well."},
{"question": "\r\n                                How long does it take to develop symptoms?\r\n                            ", "response": "The time from exposure to COVID-19 to the moment when symptoms begin is, on average, 5-6 days and can range from 1-14 days. This is why people who have been exposed to the virus are advised to stay home, apart from others, for 14 days, in order to prevent\n    the spread of the virus, especially where testing is not easily available."},
{"question": "\r\n                                What should I do if I have COVID-19 symptoms?\r\n                            ", "response": "If you have any symptoms suggestive of COVID-19, contact your health care provider or COVID-19 hotline for instructions and find out when and where to get a test, stay at home for 14 days away from others and monitor your health."},
{"question": "\r\n                                Is there a vaccine for COVID-19?\r\n                            ", "response": "Not yet. "},
{"question": "\r\n                                Are there treatments for COVID-19?\r\n                            ", "response": "Scientists around the world are working to find and develop treatments for COVID-19."},
{"question": "\r\n                                Are antibiotics effective in preventing or treating COVID-19?\r\n                            ", "response": "Antibiotics do not work against viruses; they only work on bacterial infections. COVID-19 is caused by a virus, so antibiotics do not work. Antibiotics should not be used as a means of prevention or treatment of COVID-19."}
]